Melih Gültekin

Android developer

An Android Geek for 6 years since Ice Cream Sandwich. I enjoy traveling, photography, playing table tennis, chess and coding Android apps. I always enjoy to learn and use edge technologies with open mindset. A "Harry Potter books" fan, open source lover and clean code reader.

mmelihgul	tekin@gmail.com
-----------	-----------------

+31615406239

+31615406239

Utrecht, The Netherlands

linkedin.com/in/melih-gültekin-a2a41464

github.com/melomg

TECHNICAL SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer / Android Developer

bol.com 🗷

02/2021 - Present Utrecht, The Netherlands

Achievements/Tasks

- Responsibilities: Developing new features in Kanban methodology, refactoring for code quality, publishing the app to Play Store, reviewing code, improving CI/CD.
- Worked on ads monetization.
- Developed a new Google Glass app with Jetpack Compose for a MVP.
- Implemented A/B experiments into most commonly used screens (product page, wishlist, reviews, basket, home) using MVVM
 architecture with cross platform teams.
- Introduced gradle-profiler, compose metrics jobs into the CI/CD pipelines.
- Made few contributions to KMM, iOS & backend projects.

Android Developer

Pipedrive 🗷

03/2019 - 01/2021 Tallinn, Estonia

Achievements/Tasks

- Responsibilities: Developing new features in Scrumban methodology, refactoring for code quality, publishing the app to Play Store, reviewing code, improving CI/CD.
- Changed the architecture in many places from MVC, MVP to MVVM.
- Refactored many RxJava calls to coroutines.
- Implemented new designs and changes on the most commonly used CRM features (pipelines activities) to support
 offline&online mode.
- Implemented React Native solution into the app for the React Native team.

Android Developer

Doğuş Teknoloji 🗷

01/2017 - 03/2019 Istanbul, Turkey

Achievements/Tasks

- Responsibilities: Developing new features, refactoring for code quality, publishing the app to Play Store, reviewing code, improving CI/CD.
- DOD Changed the programming language from Java to Kotlin, architecture from MVC to MVVM, implemented material design and made the app universal to support different languages.
- Scania'm Cepte Developed the network layer, new features and a custom cluster manager solution for the markers in MapView.
- Developed/maintained some features for these apps: <u>Volkswagen Ticari Arac, Scania'm Sapasaglam, Porsche Turkiye, BenimAudim, some internal apps.</u>

Page 1 of 2

WORK EXPERIENCE

Summer Intern

Computer Vision Group / Friedrich-Schiller-Universität

09/2016 - 12/2016 Jena, Germany

Achievements/Tasks

- Trained, finetuned "Bird Joints" for Tracking System with Convolutional Neural Network using Caffe Framework, tested the
 accuracy rate and evaluated regression.
- Developed Document Rectification project by using AlexNet.

SAPUI5, Javascript Developer

Inoart 🗷

03/2015 - 06/2016

Istanbul, Turkey

Achievements/Tasks

Developed several SAPUI5 apps.

EDUCATION

B. Sc. Computer Engineering - 3.29/4.00

Yıldız Technical University 🗷

09/2011 - 11/2016 Istanbul, Turkey

B. Sc. Computer Engineering - Erasmus

Warsaw University of Technology &

02/2014 - 07/2014 Warsaw, Poland

ACHIEVEMENTS

Hover Translator, Android App. Turkey GDG Mobile Hackathon Contest - 3rd in the contest. (11/2014) (11/2014 - 11/2014)

- Team members: Mustafa Berkay Mutlu, Berkay Taçyıldız

Udacity Google Developer Nanodegree Graduate (02/2018 - Present) ☑

PERSONAL PROJECTS

CurrencyConverter, Android App (In development)

 I've tried Github Packages, Github Actions, Dagger Hilt, Kotlin Flow, Coroutines, Prepoulated Room db, Layered modules with MVVM and Repository pattern.

WonderAndWander, Android App (08/2018 - Present) ☑

- A graduation app for the Udacity Nanodegree programme.
- A simple teleport app for demonstrating Java, Dagger, MVVM(ViewModel), Room, Repository Pattern, CircleCI.
- Uses popular libraries such as Room, Dagger, Retrofit, Okhttp3, Glide, Timber, Leak Canary, Places, Firebase Realtime Database, Firebase UI Auth, Fabric.

Todarch, Android App - An organization member (10/2018 - Present)

 A simple TODO playground app for me to try new things, currently in development to demonstrate MVVM, Dagger, Coroutines, AndroidX, Room, CircleCI, Repository Pattern, Clean Architecture.

Social Appointment, Android App - Graduation Project for B. Sc. (09/2015 - 05/2016)

 A simple app that is similar to Doodle which creates groups, finds free slots for people in the group for a meeting and shows percentage of availability of slots by using Google Calendar API and PHP api written by myself.

Usarsim Simulator, Android App - Pregraduation Project for B. Sc. (09/2014 - 01/2015)

An app to control simulated robots with socket communication.